<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ferdinand Theil</title>
    <link>https://www.blotz.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ferdinand Theil</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>[MIT Ferdinand Theil.](/LICENSE)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 11:37:36 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.blotz.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sourdough Bread</title>
      <link>https://www.blotz.dev/posts/recipes/sourdough-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 11:37:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blotz.dev/posts/recipes/sourdough-bread/</guid>
      <description>Sourdough is a fickle bread. The bread timings vary day to day depending on the environment you bake in and other conditions. You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t follow this recipe exactly and should do things based on what your heart desires. Only then will you achieve a beautiful home-y loaf of bread.
Sourdough Starter Care Either store your Sourdough Starter on the counter or in your fridge.
If you store your sourdough in your fridge, it will be required to be feed once a week rather than every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WannaCry</title>
      <link>https://www.blotz.dev/posts/blog/2022-07-27-wannacry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 14:35:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blotz.dev/posts/blog/2022-07-27-wannacry/</guid>
      <description>WannaCry is the largest ransomware attack. The attack started at 07:44 UTC on 12 May 2017 and was halted a few hours later at 15:03 UTC. In that time, it had spread to over 230,000 computers in 150 different countries. Companies/Agencies such as the NHS and Nissan Motor Manufacturing UK where massively crippled in this attack as they had tens of thousands of devices infected.
The widespread chaos caused by WannaCry was only possible due to a computer exploit, known as Eternal Blue, which had leaked onto the clear web a month ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Does Not Equal Random</title>
      <link>https://www.blotz.dev/posts/blog/2022-07-21-random-does-not-equal-random/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 18:42:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blotz.dev/posts/blog/2022-07-21-random-does-not-equal-random/</guid>
      <description>Random numbers are a core part of cryptography.
They are used in encryption due to the fact that it is much harder to guess a randomly generated password than it is to guess any other kind of password. This core concept has resulted in random number generation/generators becoming an integral part of cryptography.
This would be fine if it weren&amp;rsquo;t for the fact that computers suck at being random. Computers work with exactness and precision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhubarb Crumble</title>
      <link>https://www.blotz.dev/posts/recipes/rhubarb-crumble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 18:45:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blotz.dev/posts/recipes/rhubarb-crumble/</guid>
      <description>This is my own amazing rhubarb crumble recipe. There are lots of little customisations that you can do to improve the taste.
You can serve your crumble with icecream or custard. It is my favourite summer dish.
This will take 40-50 mins
Equipment Mixing bowl Saucepan Oven proof dish to bake crumble in (should be large enough to fit a single layer of rhubarb in it) Ingredients Rhubarb 600g rhubarb (cut into chunks) 75ml Orange juice or Fresh Orange 50g caster sugar Crumble 100g cold butter 200g flour 50g caster sugar 50g brown sugar (optional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Gnocchi</title>
      <link>https://www.blotz.dev/posts/recipes/homemade-gnocchi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 17:54:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blotz.dev/posts/recipes/homemade-gnocchi/</guid>
      <description>A Lovely gnocchi recipe by valentina harris. Works great for batch cooking gnocchi. I recommend creating the gnocchi on a day where you are free and freezing the extra dough as it is an intensive cook
This should take roughly 1 hour 20 mins depending on your cooking ability and if you have help.
Equipment Something to turn the boiled potato into a fine paste. something like a potato ricer or mouli Large work area for preping dough Slotted spoon Large saucepan Ingredients 1kg floury potatoes (Marfona are best but you can use King Edward) 3 large eggs 300g plain flour Instructions Cook the potatoes in boiling salted water for for 10-15 mins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wifi Hacking</title>
      <link>https://www.blotz.dev/posts/blog/2022-07-12-wifi-hacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 16:30:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blotz.dev/posts/blog/2022-07-12-wifi-hacking/</guid>
      <description>Everywhere online, i have heard that wifi was insecure.
Posts talking about WEP and WPA being insecure. WPA-2 being better but still flawed. I have decided to try and hack my own wifi router to see whether it really is insecure
Setup I am using the tp-link archer VR600 v2 as my router with WPA-2 wifi encryption. I&amp;rsquo;ll be executing my attack from my Arch Linux Laptop
Hacking my own wifi After looking around online, I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered the hashcat cracking wpawpa2 wiki article and I&amp;rsquo;ll be following along as a guide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://www.blotz.dev/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blotz.dev/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello world! My name is Ferdinand Theil, and I&amp;rsquo;m an undergraduate CS student studying in Swansea.
Welcome to my website where I post about random CS topics that I find interesting alongside wonderful recipes that I enjoy making!
Im currently looking for a part-time entry level software development job in python or java.
Check out my socials:
Github Linkedin Email Discord Buy me Coffee And don&amp;rsquo;t forget to take a look at my CV as well!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CTF submission</title>
      <link>https://www.blotz.dev/ctf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blotz.dev/ctf/</guid>
      <description>All around my website, there are hidden secrets! Find these secrets and submit them here!
Flag: Good luck!
What is a CTF CTF (Capture The Flag) is a kind of information security competition that challenges contestants to solve a variety of tasks ranging from a scavenger hunt on wikipedia to basic programming exercises. A flag is a string of text which looks like: th1s_is_an_3xampl3_fl4g These flags are hidden around the website in the files.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
