<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ferdinand Theil</title>
    <link>https://www.blotz.dev/posts/recipes/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ferdinand Theil</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>[MIT Ferdinand Theil.](/LICENSE)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 20:08:35 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.blotz.dev/posts/recipes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sourdough Bread</title>
      <link>https://www.blotz.dev/posts/recipes/sourdough-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 20:08:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blotz.dev/posts/recipes/sourdough-bread/</guid>
      <description>Sourdough is a fickle bread. The bread timings vary day to day depending on the environment you bake in and other conditions. You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t follow this recipe exactly and should do things based on what your heart desires. Only then will you achieve a beautiful home-y loaf of bread.
Sourdough Starter Care Either store your Sourdough Starter on the counter or in your fridge.
If you store your sourdough in your fridge, you need to feed it once a week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhubarb Crumble</title>
      <link>https://www.blotz.dev/posts/recipes/rhubarb-crumble/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 18:45:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blotz.dev/posts/recipes/rhubarb-crumble/</guid>
      <description>This is my own amazing rhubarb crumble recipe. There are lots of little customisations that you can do to improve the taste.
You can serve your crumble with icecream or custard. It is my favourite summer dish.
This will take 40-50 mins
Equipment Mixing bowl Saucepan Oven proof dish to bake crumble in (should be large enough to fit a single layer of rhubarb in it) Ingredients Rhubarb 600g rhubarb (cut into chunks) 75ml Orange juice or Fresh Orange 50g caster sugar Crumble 100g cold butter 200g flour 50g caster sugar 50g brown sugar (optional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade Gnocchi</title>
      <link>https://www.blotz.dev/posts/recipes/homemade-gnocchi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 17:54:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.blotz.dev/posts/recipes/homemade-gnocchi/</guid>
      <description>A Lovely gnocchi recipe by valentina harris. Works great for batch cooking gnocchi. I recommend creating the gnocchi on a day where you are free and freezing the extra dough as it is an intensive cook
This should take roughly 1 hour 20 mins depending on your cooking ability and if you have help.
Equipment Something to turn the boiled potato into a fine paste. something like a potato ricer or mouli Large work area for preping dough Slotted spoon Large saucepan Ingredients 1kg floury potatoes (Marfona are best but you can use King Edward) 3 large eggs 300g plain flour Instructions Cook the potatoes in boiling salted water for for 10-15 mins.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
